Mike Reinstein

Oakland, CA
reinstein.mike@gmail.com
https://reinstein.me
https://github.com/mreinstein

Summary / Profile

Software Developer and Manager offering twenty years of varied technical experience. Mastery of all major software product development aspects: requirements gathering, specification writing, technical leadership of both in house and remote teams, front and backend development, server operations, and Quality Assurance. Passionate open source contributor. Carbon based lifeform. Startup Junkie.

Technology

Javascript, HTML, CSS, SVG, node.js, xstate, constraint solvers, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Snabbdom, OpenGL/WebGL/three.js, deno, Apache, git, Electron, express.js, Babel/Rollup/Grunt/Gulp, Backbone, heroku, Linux, Memcache, MongoDB, MySQL, Nginx, PHP, Redis, RethinkDB, Unity, web3/solidity (Ethereum), ADA WCAG 2.1

Professional Experience

Lead Developer and Architect

Sellpoints / Syndigo Oakland, CA 7/2018 - present

At Sellpoints and Syndigo, I'm responsible for doing all of the frontend development of their enhanced content product, which runs as a third party library on almost every customer facing retail website in the world.

I transitioned the entire codebase from es5 to es6 using babel, removed jquery, re-wrote the image and video asset handling pipeline on S3 to improve bandwidth consumption, and enabled a module/nomodule approach to serve es6 to supported browsers. I adopted responsive images, and replaced useragent sniffing with feature detection. I re-wrote many of the experiences to meet ADA wcag 2.1 requirements. I led a large effort to replace font icons with svg everywhere. I also replaced the product's proprietary string concatenation based build system with rollup and adopted es modules. I enabled the usage of advanced javascript features such as async/await, and made it work even in older environments such as ie10 and up.

I also helped the company transition from Sellpoints to Syndigo which involved architecting how to merge several redundant software systems into a unified product.

Beyond specific libraries and frameworks, I've introduced several paradigms that have improved the way software is built. Using linear constraint solving I was able to build some complicated user interfaces that had previously been very difficult to maintain. I also formalized the concept of state machines in several modules, making some of the more complex code sections more robust and maintainable. I've also expanded the product's documentation, adopting a stack overflow style Q-and-A style system in markdown.

I've also handled light management duties concerning a junior developer and several contractors.

Sellpoints was acquired by Syndigo in 2019.

Self Employed Contractor

DreamingBits LLC San Francisco, CA 7/2016 - 7/2018

Shipped several web based applications, including a conversational AI agent, and a decentralized geographic land token registry powered by Ethereum. Prototyped an application based on Web Service Workers.

Lead Developer and Architect

SayMosaic San Francisco, CA 10/2015 - 6/2016

I designed and built the entire software stack that got the company accepted into the Y Combinator program. The backend is built on AWS services (EC2, ELB, Route53, Cloudfront CDN, S3, etc.) and a number of other software packages including Redis, and RethinkDB. Designed and built several iterations of the front end using plain vanilla javascript and no frameworks to produce very minimal, performant web pages. I built and open-sourced several modules on github. I also successfully handled certification of Mosaic products in the Amazon Echo and Nest app stores.

Front End Web Developer

Wrapp San Francisco, CA 11/2013 - 8/2014

I was responsible for maintaining a web application used by merchant partners. I used javascript, Backbone, Marionette, and heroku while maintaining the existing application. I refactored the code to use a subset of angularjs, which reduced complexity and improved modularity. I also established automated unit tests where there were none before.

Software Consulting

DreamingBits LLC 11/2011 - 4/2013

I worked with several companies as an independent contractor, doing work within the full software development lifecycle. Collaborated with management to design user experience, write specs, choose technology, write code, and provision the production hosting environment. Built a variety of web applications. Travelled extensively throughout India, Thailand, and Cambodia while working remotely.

Dev Manager, Lead Architect, Software Developer

FreeCause Boston, MA 2/2010 - 10/2011

Managed 10 developers in the core technology team, which was responsible for all of the search platforms, browser plugins, e-commerce platforms, and reporting platforms that powered the various business lines. As the software architect, I was responsible for designing the components and structure of these products, their interoperability, and the technical strategy for the engineering team in general. As a developer I worked on the company's toolbar and reporting platforms, working with PHP, Memcache, MySQL, several NoSQL data stores, and Amazon's Elastic MapReduce service.

Software Developer

Nokia Burlington, MA 2/2009 - 2/2010

Participated in the development of Nokia's online store. Worked on the API team, which provides an HTTP interface between the backend services and the Nokia series 40/60 devices. The OVI store initiative was eventually scaled back and canceled, but the prototype we developed used PHP5, and Memcache for it's caching layer. Responsibilities included requirement gathering, developer documentation, unit testing, and implementation. Used a mix of agile, waterfall, and iterative process.

Software Developer

Skyhook Wireless Boston, MA 3/2007 - 9/2008

Responsible for the data acquisition platform written in win32 and C# running on an iPAQ PDA. Wrote a web based management system in PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, and Javascript. The management tool handles many operational aspects: hiring drivers, payroll, and driver statistics analysis. Also developed a simple GIS application to monitor driver tracks, coverage, and cost. Managed an offshore team of three developers that assisted with development.

Security Tester

Security Innovation Wilmington, MA 10/2005 - 2/2007

Performed exploratory testing, threat modeling, test plan development, test execution, results analysis, and reporting for Microsoft, Compuware, Credit Suisse, and RSA. My other duties included security product research, and the production of e-Learning materials coursework. I took initiative within the internal operations group to transition the company's knowledge-base into a wiki. I helped maintain the company's source control system (Subversion) and an internal application server (LAMP stack.)

Software Developer

The Plum Group Boston, MA 1/2003 - 1/2005

I was responsible for developing Voice XML applications for various clients. I assisted as a technical writer in documenting the flagship product "Plum Voice Platform". I helped deploy and maintain a content management system and user forum to establish formal customer support. I occasionally acted as sales engineer. I shared responsibilities of the systems operations department including server monitoring, disaster recovery, internal toolset, development, and software repository maintenance.

Personal Experience

Game Publishing

Self Employed San Francisco, CA 8/2014 - present

I've been working on shipping a game based on an idea I've had for a long time. The product is based on web technology: Javascript, WebGL, and Electron as the app container. This is an extremely large project, and I work on it in a hobby capacity as time permits.

Co-founder

Datesite.com Boston, MA 4/2006 - 7/2007

I created a website that allows people with mutual crushes to locate each other in a non-confrontational way. There were over fifty thousand signups which we achieved without spending any money on marketing, due to the low operating costs associated with viral growth. The application re-uses the framework that I created for Himatomo, one of my previous endeavors. I was responsible for all aspects of the software development.

Co-founder

Himatomo.com Boston, MA 5/2004 - 10/2005

I created a framework and mobile website specifically for Japanese cell phones using PHP, MySQL, and HTML. The site contained several advanced features including a mobile blog, a college-oriented social network inspired by FaceBook, and a location-based friend locator service. Designed clear and black box tests using PHPUnit and JUnit. I helped the business team by guiding the requirements gathering process, and the subsequent documentation. I designed the operational infrastructure to host the service in production and staging environments. Lead the internationalization team to ensure the platform reliably handled English (iso 8859-1) and Japanese (euc-jp, sjis), as well as drop-in support for additional locales.

Education

Plattsburgh State University of New York (SUNY)

1996 - 2002

Pursued a B.S in Computer Science program.